BETH: Reasonable adjustments are a
way of ensuring that every individual
with autism has equal access to
services and facilities, by reducing
or alleviating disadvantage.
Some services may need to provide
more suitable support to individuals
with autism, in order for them to
achieve the same outcomes as others.
Each individual with autism spectrum
disorder is unique, with different needs
and challenges, therefore a comprehensive
assessment may need to be carried out,
to identify their specific areas of need.
JOE: The Equality Act 2010 requires
reasonable adjustments to be made, so as
to avoid individuals with a disability
being put at a "substantial disadvantage"
compared with those without a disability.
This also applies to
individuals with autism.
BETH: All service providers and public
bodies have a duty, to ensure that
individuals with autism, have equal
access to healthcare, education,
leisure and all other services
regardless of their specific needs.
Therefore, if they cannot access
those services and facilities, then
reasonable adjustments need to be made.
JOE: To benefit individuals with
autism, reasonable adjustments,
should be relevant to their needs.
Some adjustments may be straightforward
or simple, others may be more complex.
This may involve things like
lighting, ambient noise, visual
aids, quiet rooms and easy access.
BETH: Some reasonable adjustments can
be done quite easily and cheaply, some
may be more involved and costly, but it
is important that they should be made if
they benefit the individuals with autism.